FESTUS KIPROTICH KOECH

P.O BOX 1005 KERICHO 0722444727 | koechbor1@gmail.com

Personal Details

Date of Birth : 13/09/2002
Marital Status : Single
Nationality : Kenyan

Objective

I seek challenging opportunities where I can fully use my skills for the success of the organization. I am an experienced software developer. I bring more than four years experience writing JavaScript and more than four years experience in the technology industry and To enhance my professional skills, capabilities and knowledge in an organization which recognizes the value of hard work and trusts me with responsibilities and challenges.

Education

• KABARAK UNIVERSITY 2023 -ongoing

HCIA Cloud Computing V5.0 & Bachelor of Science in computer science and Bi-informatics Mock exam 96% (A)

• KABARAK UNIVERSITY 2019-2021

Computer Science CREDIT

• SOLIAT BOYS HIGH SCHOOL 2015-2018

KCSE

• LALIAT PRIMARY SCHOOL 2014

KCPE

Experience

KENYA POWER AND LIGHTNING COMPANY

3/7/2021 - 30/9/2023

IT SKILLED CASUAL

- Networking, installation, Configuration and Trouble shooting Cisco routers ,switches ,phones.
- System and application software installation and maintenance.
- Repair of Network printers ,personal computers and installation of new components.
- Troubleshooting WAN and LAN.
- Installation and configuration of digital modems and IP phone's.
- User support in day to day operations.
- Working with fibre optic cable including splicing.
- Working in Radio Repeater sites ad Mobile Radio communication.
- Power systems communication SCADA Systems

KENYA POWER AND LIGHTNING COMPANY

3/10/2022 - 2/12/2022

ELECTRICAL TRAINEE

- Practice Electrical and Mechanical Safety Rules &Codes of procedure and practices the operations and maintenance of network.
- Revenue collection with aid of smart meters ,remotely Disconnection /Reconnection.
- Metering of Large Power Meters.
- Troubleshooting of Non Communicating Smart meters.
- Customer Queries
- Installation of new Meters ,Meter verification & Installation of Check meters.
- Inspection for faulty Meters & Installation of check Meters.
- Simple Energy audit & Meter Verification for accuracy.

Skills

- · Computer Programming.
- Motivate to work with little supervision
- · Managing Priorities
- · Coaching
- · Hardworking and industrious
- · Self discipline

Achievements & Awards

- · INVENTED AND PROGRAMMED WORK SCHOOL MANAGEMENT FOR BRILLIANT ACADEMY.
- · BEST STUDENT DURING KPLC ATTACHMENT FROM MAY-JULY PERIOD AND RETAINED ON CONTRACT
- I HAVE MADE MY PERSONAL WEBSITE

Reference

• DR.SHADRACK BETT - KABARAK UNIVERSITY

H.O.D Bettshad@gmail.com 0721730594

• ENG. ROSALYNE MWIKHALI KARANJA - KENYA POWER AND LIGHTNING COMPANY

ICT ENGINEER INCHARGE NORTHRIFT REGION Rkaranja@kplc.co.ke 0733991303

• CHRISTINE CHEMTAI MULWA - KENYA POWER AND LIGHTNING COMPANY

HUMAN RESOURCE OFFICER 1 CChemutaimulwa@kplc.co.ke 0722141039

• CEC HON. ELIJAH KOSGEY - COUNTY GOVERNMENT OF UASIN GISHU COUNTY

CECM PUBLIC SERVICE AND DEVOLUTION elijahkosgei87@gmail.com 0724021307